Erich Maria Remarque Papers, 1918-2000 (bulk 1950s - 1980s) MSS.095
Fales Library and Special Collections
Erich Maria Remarque Papers
1918-2000
Fales Library and Special Collections
Remarque, Erich Maria, 1898-1970
MSS.095
21 Linear Feet
Provenance
The bulk of the materials were transferred between 1993 and 2000 from the offices of Richard Kay, who served as a legal and financial advisor to Paulette Goddard. Many of the documents appear to have previously come from the offices of Harriet Pilpel, Erich Remarque's attorney and friend.
Scope and Content
The Erich Remarque Papers Accretion consists of correspondence, notes and contracts primarily dealing with the financial and legal aspects of Remarque's life and works. It also includes ephemera and some audiovisual recordings documenting adaptations of works by Remarque; a small selection of typed short story mauscripts with handwritten notes; some personal correspondence and photographs of Paulette Goddard; correspondence, photos, financial statements and auction catalogs related to the Remarques collections of art, textiles, jewelry and other decorative arts; as well as a small amount of photographs that appear to show city and country scenes in Germany.
This guide describes an accretion to the Erich Maria Remarque Papers. An additional 63 boxes are detailed in a German language inventory available from the Fales Library. Please contact fales.library@nyu.edu for further assistance.
Arrangement
The Erich Maria Remarque Papers Accretion is organized into the following nine series:
Series I: Literary properties consists of correspondence, memos, contracts, agreements, drafts, royalty statements and notes related to the financial and legal aspects of novels, plays, short stories, articles and screenplays by Erich Maria Remarque, as well as related adaptations. It is organized into subseries arranged alphabetically by work title. Within each subseries, materials are arranged chronologically, and photocopies are filed based on dates of the originals.
Series II: General financial and legal consists of correspondence, memos, tax returns and other financial and legal documents of Erich Remarque and Paulette Goddard not primarily related to Remarques' literary output. It is arranged chronologically.
Series III: Art, textile and jewelry collections consists of documents related to the Remarques' collections of art, textiles, jewelry and other decorative objects. Subseries A: Correspondence and financial documents contains correspondence with auction houses, as well as sales statements. Subseries B: Catalogs contains primarily auction catalogs, many with handwritten notes and sales statements, as well as one non-auction catalog. Unless otherwise stated, the catalogs are from Sotheby's auction house.
Series IV: Short story manuscripts consists of mostly typed manuscripts, many with handwritten notes. It is arranged alphabetically by story title.
Series V: Paulette Goddard personal materials consists of correspondence, engagement books and planners. The bulk of the correspondence is from Paulette Goddard to her mother, Alta Goddard, although it includes letters from Erich Maria Remarque and several other correspondents to Paulette Goddard.
Series VI: Eleonara Duse telegrams contains a small number of telegrams from actress Eleonara Duse to theater director Paul Lindau. They have been retained in original order.
Series VII: Photographs consists of photographs and glass plate negatives, and is separated into three subseries. Subseries A: Erich Remarque consists of photos that appear to date from the 1920s and 1930s and include images of cars, city scenes, and country roads with many pictures of an unidentified woman. Subseries B: Paulette Goddard consists primarily of film promotional stills, along with some personal shots. Subseries C: Art, furniture, jewelry, rugs consists of photos primarily of items belonging to the Remarques that appear to have been used in appraisals and sales.
Series VIII: Film contains one film that is currently unavailable to researchers.
Series IX: Audio and Video recordings consists of at least one interview with Erich Remarque, along with a number of unidentified cassettes. All audio and video recordings are currently unavailable to researchers.
Series X: Objects consists of a handbag and portrait locket belonging to Paulette Goddard
Biographical / Historical
Novelist Erich Maria Remarque was born on June 22, 1898 in Osnabrück, Germany. He spent his childhood in imperial Osnabrück, and later served in the German army in World War I on the Western Front. Remarque's books were burned and banned in Nazi Germany, and he lived in exile in Switzerland and the United States following the revocation of his German citizenship in 1938. Remarque married, divorced, and remarried Ilse Jutta Zambona. In 1958 he married American actress Paulette Goddard, and they remained married until his death.
Remarque is best known for his novel All Quiet On the Western Front, which was first published in 1929. His other published novels include The Road Back (1931), Three Comrades (1936, 38), Flotsam (1941), Arch of Triumph (1945), The Black Obelisk (1956), Heaven Has No Favorites (1961), and The Night in Lisbon (1962). Many of these works were adapted into films, often shortly after their publication. According to the Erich Maria Remarque-Peace Center, Remarque critically examined German history in his works, upholding "the preservation of human dignity and humanity in times of oppression, terror and war." Remarque died on September 25, 1970 in Locarno, Switzerland.
Sources: http://www.remarque.uni-osnabrueck.de/internet.htm
http://remarque.org/about_remarque.html
Related Materials
Erich Maria Remarque Papers
Paulette Goddard Papers (unprocessed)
Fales Manuscript Collection (contains Goethe manuscripts believed to have belonged to Erich Remarque)
Julie Gilbert Papers
New American Library Archive
Separated Materials
The following books were removed to be catalogued:
Erich Maria Remarque Jahrbuch/Yearbook I/1991
Pirchan, Emil. Buehnen Brevier.
Reue ist undeutsch.
Spoto, Donald. Blue Angel. (1992)
Marlene Dietrich's ABC (1962)
Inscribed to "Mein lieber Alfred" signed "Tante Lena" - Marlene by Marlene Dietrch (1989)
Man Kann alten Dreck nicht vergraben, er fängt immer wieder an zu stinken :Materialien zu einem Erich Maria Remarque-Projekt der Universität Osnabrück, Fachbereich Sprache, Literatur, Medien und zu der Inszenierung der Probebühne Der schwarze Obelisk, eine Textkollage /.[herausgegeben von Lothar Schwindt und Tilman Westphalen]..
Der schwarze Obelisk: eine Textkollage: Stück in 36 Bildern nach dem gleichnamigen Roman und unter Verwendung anderer Romane Erich Maria Remarques sowie von Originaldokumenten / erarbeitet auf der Grundlage des Entwurfs einer Bühnenfassung "Der schwarze Obelisk, Geschichte einer verspäteten Jugend" in drei Teilen von Hans Jürgen Meyer durch eine Projektgruppe der Universität Osnabrück, Fachbereich Sprache, Literatur, Medien im WS 1982/83 und SS 1983, Harald Keller ... [et al.]; Endredaktion, Tilman Westphalen.
Krieg und Literatur
Sekundärmaterial in Auswahl
Erich Maria Remarque ein Weltbürger wider Willen (partly in Russian)
Mitteilungen der Erich Maria Remarque Gesellschaft Osnabrueck E.V. Heft 4 September 1988
Erich Maria Remarque: der Weg Zurück: eine Ausstellung / [herausgegeben vom Vorstand der Erich Maria Remarque Gesellschaft e.V., Osnabrück; in Zusammenarbeit mit dem Erich Maria Remarque Archiv/Forschungsstelle Krieg und Literatur, Universität Osnabrück; Bild- und Textredaktion: Brigitte Jorden-Kellermeier und Detlef Vornkahl; in Zusammenarbeit mit Thomas Schneider; Kataloggestaltung und Ausstellungsdesign: Michael Fischer.
Das Erich Maria Remarque-Archiv Osnabrück / [herausgegeben vom Erich Maria Remarque-Archiv/Forschungsstelle Krieg und Literatur im Auftrag von Stadt und Universität Osnabrück; Redaktion: Claudia Glunz].
The Hurrell Style: 50 Years of Photographing Hollywood
What becomes a Legend most?: The Blackgama Story by Peter Rogers
with inscription to Paulette from author
Savini un nome nella storia
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Other Finding Aids
An additional 63 boxes are detailed in a German language inventory available from the Fales Library. Please contact fales.library@nyu.edu for further assistance.
Personal correspondence.; Paperbacks.; Novels.; Novelists, German |y 20th century.; Paperbacks |x Publishing |z United States |x History |y 20th century.; Paintings (visual works); New York (N.Y.).; German Americans |x Ethnic identity.; Financial records; Briefs (legal documents); Booksellers and bookselling; Black-and-white negatives.; Black-and-white photographs.; Authors and publishers.; Art -- Collectors and collecting.; Art objects -- Collectors and collecting.; Appointment books.; Administrative records.; Actresses -- United States.; Acting.; Accounts.; Business records.; Collectors and collecting.; Motion picture plays.; Motion pictures.; Marginalia (annotations); Motion picture actors and actresses.; Manuscripts; Manuscripts for publication.; Literature publishing -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Manuscript preparation (Authorship).; Legal documents.; Literary agents.; Law |z New York (State) |x History.; Legal correspondence.; Hollywood (Los Angeles, Calif.); Law |z United States |x History.; German Americans |z New York (State) |z New York.; Holocaust.; Translations |x Literature.; Writings (document genre); Theater.; Theatrical publishing.; Tax returns.; Television plays.; Fiction |y 20th century.; Editor author correspondence.; Editing; Drama.; Drafts (documents); Datebooks.; Correspondence.; Contracts; Tax records.; Publishers and publishing |z United States |v Correspondence.; Publishers and publishing; Postcards.; Photographs.; Personal papers.; Film.; Film stills.
- Original Accession (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3, Box 4, Box 5, Box 6, Box 7, Box 8, Box 9, Box 10, Box 11, Box 12, Box 13, Box 14, Box 15, Box 16, Box 17, Box 18, Box 19, Box 20, Box 21, Box 22, Box 23, Box 24, Box 25, Box 26, Box 27, Box 28, Box 29, Box 30, Box 31, Box 32, Box 33, Box 34, Box 35, Box 36, Box 37, Box 38, Box 39, Box 40, Box 41, Box 43, Box 44, Box 45, Box 46, Box 47, Box 48, Box 49, Box 50, Box 52, Box 51, Box 53, Box 54, Box 55, Box XII.A.1, Box XII.A.2, Box XII.A.3, Box XII.A.4, Box XII.A.5, Box XII.B.1, Box XII.B.2, Box XII.B.3)
  Other Finding Aids
  An additional 63 boxes are detailed in a German language inventory available from the Fales Library. Please contact fales.library@nyu.edu for further assistance.
- 2003 Accretion
  - Series I: Literary properties, 244336
    Scope and Content
    Series I: Literary properties consists of correspondence, memos, contracts, agreements, drafts, royalty statements and notes related to the financial and legal aspects of novels, plays, short stories, articles and screenplays by Erich Maria Remarque, as well as related adaptations. It is organized into subseries arranged alphabetically by work title. Within each subseries, materials are arranged chronologically, and photocopies are filed based on dates of the originals.
    - Subseries A: All Quiet on the Western Front, 244470
      - Agreement of Release between Remarque and Little Brown and Company regarding All Quiet on the Western Front copyright (unsigned), 1958; 244498 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Manuscript Appraisal, 1961; 244499 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Conrad Homberger request for reprint permission in German language reader, 1963; 244500 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence and drafts with publishers including Putnam's, Little Brown, Noble & Noble, Fawcett, Crest over English language rights, 1959-1963; 244501 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Library of Congress recording for the blind - correspondence and signed agreement, 1961, 1965; 244560 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Print and film rights and tax advice - drafts and correspondence, 1958-1968; 244561 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - English language rights - correspondence and memos, 1966-1973; 244562 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Japanese radio dramatization rights - correspondence, 1977; 244563 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Franklin Library deluxe edition proposal, 1978; 244564 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - CBS Television Reading Program - Letter and promotional materials, 1979; 244565 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Motion Picture Rights Agreement with Marble Arch Productions, 1979; 244566 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - A Race to Nowhere - An Arms Race Primer for Catholics with excerpt, circa 1980; 244567 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Fawcett Publications - royalty statements, 1958-1981; 244568 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Movie rights - correspondence and memos, 1977-1981; 244569 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - ITC Productions - statements and correspondence, 1982-1983; 244570 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Copy of Screenplay Adaptation by Del Andrews, Dialogue by Maxwell Anderson and George Abbott, 1985 (original 1929); 244571 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Permissions (1 of 2), 1970-1985; 244600 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Permissions (2 of 2), 1970-1985; 244601 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Noble and Noble - Royalty Statements, 1972-1985; 244602 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Permissions, 1979-1985; 244603 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Permissions (1 of 2), 1975-1986; 244604 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Permissions (2 of 2), 1975-1986; 244605 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Permissions, 1983-1986; 244680 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Permissions, 1985-1988; 244681 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Movie Rights, 1967-1989; 244682 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Permissions, 1989-1990; 244683 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Permissions, 1986-1992; 244684 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Contract and related material - Ballantine Paperback, 1958-1990; 244692 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Agreement, royalty statements and related material - MBI Books, 244693 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Subseries B: Arch of Triumph, 244697
      - Correspondence and memos, 1945-1946; 244740 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Contract drafts with Arch of Triumph Inc, Enterprise and Lewis and related correspondence, notes and memos, 1946 July - October; 244741 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Book publication with Appleton Century - correspondence and memos, 1945-1946; 244742 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence and memos, 1946-1948; 244744 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Film rights - correspondence and memos, 1945-1948; 244748 (Box 4, Folder 5)
        General
        Primarily in English; four letters in German.
      - Correspondence and memos, 1948-1949; 244749 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Settlement with Enterprise Productions, 1949; 244750 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence regarding dispute with American Broadcasting Company over Madame Madou character in Cafe Istanbul, 1952; 244751 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Contract with David Lewis and correspondence, 1945-1956; 244753 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - TV rights - correspondence and memos, 1955-1959; 244755 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Night Flight promotional material - prior presentation of The Singer Company, circa 1979; 244756 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Contract with New American Library dated 9/12/1984, related correspondence and royalty statements, 1984-1989; 244759 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Permissions, 1983; 244760 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Takarazuka musical stage adaptation publicity materials (1 of 2), 1999-2000; 244761 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Takarazuka musical stage adaptation publicity materials 2 of 2, 1999-2000; 244762 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Subseries C: Black Obelisk, 244698
      - Agreements with Harcourt Brace and Company, 1952-1956; 244805 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Agreement with Collier Publishing Company, 1955; 244806 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Agreement with Collier Publishing Company - drafts, 1954-1956; 244807 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - [Typed] Manuscript translated by Denver Lindley (partial) with list of readers, 1956; 244808 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - [Typed] Manuscript 1 (1 of 2), circa 1956; 244809 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - [Typed] Manuscript 1 (2 of 2), circa 1956; 244810 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - [Typed] Manuscript 2 (1 of 2), circa 1956; 244811 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - [Typed] Manuscript 2 (2 of 2), circa 1956; 244812 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence and memos primarily with publishers and production companies, 1955-1957; 244813 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Newspaper reviews and advertisements, 1957; 244814 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - TV rights, 1957; 244815 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Foreign rights, 1957-1958; 244816 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        Primarily in English; one letter in German with English translation.
      - Motion picture rights (1 of 2), 1957-1973; 244819 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Motion picture rights (2 of 2), 1957-1973; 244820 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Permissions - Library of Congress recording for the blind, 1978; 244821 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence and memos regarding film and print rights, 1957-1980; 244822 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Motion picture rights - correspondence and memos, 244833 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - German TV production - Agreement drafts and copies, correspondence and memos, 1986-1988; 244834 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Royalties, 1983-1991; 244835
    - Subseries D: Heaven Has No Favorites (serialized as Borrowed Life), 244699
      - Draft contracts with Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1952-1959; 244866 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Letter from Frank Dukas about copyright notice with excerpt in Zuercher Woche, 1959; 244867 (Box 6, Folder 12)
        Letter is in German with English translation.
      - Movie - correspondence and memos, 1960 January - March; 244868 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Good Housekeeping magazine serialization - extra copies and drafts, 1960; 244869 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Contract - Good Housekeeping, 1960; 244908 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Contract - Columbia Pictures Corporations and related materials including rights summary, 1959-1961; 244909 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence and drafts, 1959-1961; 244910 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Book - Copies and drafts, 1960-1961; 244911 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Movie - correspondence and memos, 1960-1961; 244912 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - EMR - Borrowed Life - Heaven Has No Favorites - Movie - Drafts and Extra Copies, 1960-1961; 264603 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Borrowed Life - Copyright, Copies and Drafts, 1961; 264604 (Box 7, Folder 4A)
      - German edition (book) - memos, 1961; 245040 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Foreign rights - correspondence, 1961; 245055 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Copyright - correspondence and memos, 245063 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Good Housekeeping Magazine serialization - correspondence and memos, 1959-1964; 245064 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Contract - Employment Agreement with Columbia Pictures Corporation, 1960-1964; 245065 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Movie - Investments, 1959-1973; 245066 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Contract with Columbia Motion Pictures Corporations, 1960-1976; 245067 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Bobby Deerfield - Columbia Pictures distribution statements, 1979-1980; 245068 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Movie - "Historical Interest" memos and draft agreements, 1960-1975; 245069 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Bobby Deerfield - financial statements from Columbia Pictures, 1978-1981; 245070 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Plagiarism claim, 1982, undated; 245071 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Movie - correspondence and memos (1 of 2), 1961-1983; 245184 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Movie - correspondence and memos (2 of 2), 1961-1983; 245185 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Bobby Deerfield - correspondence and Columbia Pictures financial statements, 1983-1985; 245186 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Permissions, 1985; 245187 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Vecko Revyn Magazine with Serialized Borrowed Life (Swedish), undated; 252959 (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Kristall Magazine (German) with Serialized Geborgtes Leben, 1959; 252960 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Subseries E: The Homecoming of Enoch J. Jones, 244779
      - Photocopied script, circa 1988; 245183 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Photocopied scripts (1 of 4), circa 1988; 245188 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Photocopied scripts (2 of 4), circa 1988; 245189 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Photocopied scripts (3 of 4), circa 1988; 245190 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Photocopied scripts (4 of 4), circa 1988; 245196 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Osnabrueck University "Remarque Year" performance (1 of 2), 1985-1989; 245218 (Box 9, Folder 2)
        Some material in German.
      - Osnabrueck University "Remarque Year" performance (2 of 2), 1985-1989; 245220 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Subseries F: The Last Act, 245221
      - American Weekly, Saturday Review, 1952-1955; 245226 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Subseries G: The Last Station, 244790
      - Contract with producer Otto Preminger (draft), 1956; 245223 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Renaissance Theater Program, 1956; 264274 (Box 9, Folder 5A)
      - Permissions correspondence, 1980; 245224 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Permissions, 1983; 245225 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Permissions, 1980-1990; 245239 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Permissions, undated; 245240 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Subseries H: Night in Lisbon, 244791
      - Manuscript Die Nacht von Lissabon - typed, bound (1 of 2), circa 1961; 245241 (Box 9, Folder 10)
        Manuscript is in German.
      - Manuscript Die Nacht von Lissabon - typed, bound (2 of 2), circa 1961; 245242 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence and memos, 1956-1964; 245248 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence and memos, 1964-1980; 245249 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Permissions (German and English language rights), 1983-1984; 245250 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Subseries I: The Other Love, 245254
      - Agreement with David Lewis and David Loew - drafts and working papers, 1945-1946; 245270 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Stock agreement with Enterprise Productions Inc, 1946; 245271 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - News clipping about agreement with David Lewis and David Loew, 1946; 245272 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence and draft agreements with David Lewis and David Loew, 1946-1947; 245273 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence and memos, 1947-1949; 245274 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Subseries J: The Road Back, 244792
      - Contract with Universal Pictures Company, 1939-1948; 245265 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Contract with Avon Book Division - Hearst Corp. (unsigned), 1950s; 245266 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Contract with Universal Pictures (photostat), 1956; 245267 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Copy of Avon reprint contract and related, 1951-1962; 245268 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence. memos, drafts, 1962-1981; 245269 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Permissions, 1984; 245336 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Movie rights - correspondence and memos, 1975-1992; 245337 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Subseries K: Shadows in Paradise, 244793
      - "New York Story" - unsigned contract with Harcourt Brace Jovanovish (photocopy), circa 1970; 245340 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - "New York Story" - correspondence and memos, 1970-1971; 245341 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence and memos, 1971; 245345 (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence, 1976-1982; 245346 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Subseries L: So Ends Our Night (originally published as Flotsam), 244794
      - Contract with Loew's Incorporated (photostat copy) and related correspondence and memos, 1939-1974; 245348 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Subseries M: Spark of Life, 244795
      - Notes and working papers, 1945; 245349 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Draft of contract with Appleton, 1946; 245352 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence and memos, 1946-1950; 245353 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Contract, Cancellation Letter with Appleton, 1946, 1950; 245354 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Amendatory letter with Appleton, 1950-1951; 245355 (Box 11, Folder 5)